Douglas Benton papers, 1941-1996 (bulk 1950-1996)
UCLA Library Special Collections
Douglas Benton papers
Bulk, 1950-1996
1941-1996 (bulk 1950-1996)
2216
UCLA Library Special Collections
12.8 linear ft. (28 boxes and 4 flat boxes)
Douglas Benton was a television writer, director, and producer who was best known his work in detective show genres. The collection consists of script material and production information and material documenting his production company, Blackjack Productions.
Benton, Douglas
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. STORED OFF-SITE AT SRLF. Advance notice is required for access to the collection. Please contact UCLA Library Special Collections for paging information.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Mrs. Jacqueline Benton, 2013.
Biography
Douglas Carleton Benton II was born on September 24, 1925 in Hollis, Oklahoma and spent most of his childhood in West Texas. Benton earned a B.A. at the University of New Mexico (1948) and a Master of Science in Journalism at Northwestern University (1950). He began his career making documentary films for General Electric and was later placed in charge of the series General Electric Theater in Hollywood, CA. From there he went on to write and produce television series for Universal, MGM, and other studios. Benton's credits include Dr. Kildare (1961-1966), Hec Ramsey (1972-1974), Columbo, Police Woman, (1974-1978), and Magnum, P.I. (early-1980s), among others. He produced and directed several movies for television, among them A Holwing in the Woods, Undercover with the Ku Klux Klan, and MADD: Mothers Against Drunk Driving. Nominated a number of times for an Emmy, Benton earned the award in 1974 for his work on the series, Columbo. Benton died in November 2000.
Scope and Content
The collection consists of material related to the career of television writer, director, and producer Douglas Benton. The bulk of the collection consists of scripts and treatments for television projects. Produced television projects represented include Dr. Kildare, Columbo, The Girl from U.N.C.L.E., Hec Ramsey, and Policewoman, among others. Additionally, there is a small amount of production information, material related to Blackjack Productions, Benton's production company, a small amount of correspondence, both business and personal, script submissions, and a very small number of photographs.
Organization and Arrangement
Arranged in the following series:
Biographical and Personal information
Television Projects
Black Jack Productions
Projects in Development
Submissions to Benton
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 7407396
Benton, Douglas--Archives; Television producers and directors--Archives
Container List
- Biographical and Personal.
  - Benton Resumes., no dates. (Box 1)
  - Benton's Northwestern University Masters degree diploma., 1950. (Box 25)
  - Benton's University of New Mexico Bachelor of Arts diploma., 1948. (Box 1)
  - Holographic Notes., no dates. (Box 6)
  - Personal letters to Benton., ca. 1975. (Box 22)
  - TV Producer Benton Says Censors Strangling Shows - article clipping., 1972 Sept 30. (Box 22)
    From the Columbia Record Entertainment Week publication.
- Television Projects.
  - Academy of Television Arts and Sciences 1979-1980 Entry Cards Emmy Awards., 1977-1980. (Box 24)
  - Memo and Budgets., 1987. (Box 5)
    Appears to be for In Search of Eden and Immortal Outcast.
  - Blacke's Magic - script., 1985 Sept 30. (Box 1)
  - Caper - script., no dates. (Box 8)
    See also: Dead President, Rare Coin Heist, and Rare Coin Score.
  - Cimarron Strip (Greece) (2 folders)., 1987-1989. (Box 1)
  - Columbo - Any Old Port in a Storm script., 1973 Mar 12. (Box 1)
  - Columbo - Any Old Port in a Storm script and shooting schedule., 1973 Mar 2. (Box 1)
  - Columbo - Beauty is as Beauty Dies script and promotional billboard document., 1973 Mar 8. (Box 1)
  - Columbo - Candidate for Murder script and memo., 1973 Feb 7. (Box 1)
  - Columbo - Emmy Award program and well wishes., 1974. (Box 1)
  - Columbo - Mind Over Mayhem script., 1973 Jan 24. (Box 1)
  - Columbo - National Academy of Television Arts and Sciences (The) Nomination for Outstanding Limited Series., 1973-1974. (Box 28)
  - Correspondence to and from Benton., 1969-1973. (Box 6)
  - Cry for Help (A) - production information., ca. 1978. (Box 6)
  - Cry for Help (A) - script and production information., 1978. (Box 5)
  - Dr. Kildare - staff list and schedule., 1961-1966. (Box 1)
  - Drill (The) - script., no dates. (Box 11)
  - Enos - master plot., no dates. (Box 1)
  - Foxfire - script., 1984 Nov and Dec. (Box 4)
  - Gauguin the Savage - production information (fka In Search of Eden)., ca. 1979. (Box 6)
    See also: In Search of Eden.
  - Girl from U.N.C.L.E. - character faces memo., 1966 May 18. (Box 2)
  - Girl from U.N.C.L.E. - Carpathian Affair (The) script., 1966 Nov 23. (Box 2)
  - Girl from U.N.C.L.E. - Danish Blue Affair (The) script., 1966 July 7. (Box 2)
  - Girl from U.N.C.L.E. - Faustus Affair (The) script., 1966 Aug 16. (Box 2)
  - Girl from U.N.C.L.E. - Lethal Eagle Affair (The) script., 1966 Aug 3. (Box 2)
  - Girl from U.N.C.L.E. - Misused Magic Affair (The) script., 1966 Aug 3. (Box 2)
  - Girl from U.N.C.L.E. - Season 1966-1967 reader's report. (Box 2)
  - Girl from U.N.C.L.E. - Atlantis Affair (The) script., 1966 Jan 13. (Box 2)
  - Girl from U.N.C.L.E. - Furnace Flats Affair (The)script., 1966 Aug 10. (Box 2)
  - Girl from U.N.C.L.E. - Little John Doe s Affair (The) script., 1966 Aug 15. (Box 2)
  - Girl from U.N.C.L.E. and Man from U.N.C.L.E. - schedules., 1966-1967. (Box 1)
  - Hec Ramsey - Blood Money script., 1972 July 17. (Box 2)
    Binder labeled Karl Turner
  - Hec Ramsey - Dixie Comin' Through script., 1972 Aug 16. (Box 2)
  - Hec Ramsey - Fly Paper script., 1972 May 23. (Box 3)
    Binder labeled Girard and Lane
  - Hec Ramsey - Green Feather (The) script., 1972 July 11. (Box 2)
  - Hec Ramsey - Guerrilleros (The) script., 1972 July 21. (Box 2)
    Binder labeled Jim Byrnes
  - Hec Ramsey - Last Battle (The) script., 1972 June 14. (Box 3)
  - Hec Ramsey - Yellow Rose (The) script., 1972 Aug 22. (Box 2)
  - Howling in the Woods (A) - 2 scripts., 1969 and 1970. (Box 4)
  - In Our Hands - script and production information., 1981. (Box 5)
  - In Search of Eden - production information., 1978. (Box 23)
    See also: Gauguin the Savage.
  - Inside the KKK (Freedom Fighters) - script and production information., 1978. (Box 5)
  - Ironside - Come In, Come In, Whoever You Are script., no dates. (Box 3)
  - Ironside - Connoisseur of Crime (Old Contract Plus Story Ideas)., ca. 1972. (Box 9)
  - Ironside - master television plot., ca. 1970. (Box 3)
  - Ironside - National Academy of Television Arts and Sciences (The) Nomination for Outstanding Dramatic Series., 1968-1969. (Box 27)
  - Ironside - National Academy of Television Arts and Sciences (The) Nomination for Outstanding Dramatic Series., 1969-1970. (Box 27)
  - Ironside - National Academy of Television Arts and Sciences (The) Nomination for Outstanding Series - Drama., 1970-1971. (Box 27)
  - Ironside - production information (from binder labeled Ironside 1968)., 1968-1969. (Box 3)
  - Ironside - schedule and cast sheets., 1969-1971. (Box 3)
  - Jake and the Fatman - Lady in Red (The) script., 1989 July 14. (Box 3)
  - Jake and the Fatman - My Heart Belongs to Daddy., 1990 Mar 15. (Box 3)
  - Jake and the Fatman - Untitled script (2 items) and Killing Me Softly story outline., 1989 July 14. (Box 3)
  - Last Cry for Help - Film Advisory Board award., 1979. (Box 25)
  - MADD: Mothers Against Drunk Driving - American Women in Radio and Television award., 1983. (Box 25)
  - Magnum P.I. - Acdemy of Television Arts and Sciences Nomination for Outstanding Drama Series., 1983-1984. (Box 28)
  - Magnum P.I. - production information., 1980-1983. (Box 3)
  - Mother Against Drunk Driving: The Candy Lightner Story - revised script., 1982 Nov 1. (Box 5)
  - Mounted publication covers and photograph., 1979 and 1980. (Box 26)
  - Murder She Wrote - Academy of Television Arts and Sciences Nomination for Outstanding Drama Series., 1985. (Box 28)
  - Name of the Game - revised promo., 1968 Feb 19 and 23. (Box 5)
  - Photographs and Slides (15 items)., 1962, 1966, 1973, and 1981. (Box 24)
    Douglas Benton (alone and with others); Eddie Andrews, Richard Boone, Karen Bresler, and Joseph Naar.
  - Police Woman - plaque., no dates. (Box 24)
  - Policewoman - Battered Teachers script., 1977 Nov 23. (Box 3)
  - Policewoman - staff and crew list., 1975 and 1977. (Box 3)
  - Policewoman - Sweet Kathleen script., 1977 Dec 23. (Box 3)
  - Policewoman - Task Force Cop Killer script., 1975 Dec 21. (Box 4)
  - Policewoman - Trick Book (The) (part I) script., 1976 May 28. (Box 4)
  - Presentations., 1960-1962. (Box 7)
    Have You Met Miss Jones, White Walls, Sweet Are the Uses of Perversity among others.
  - Punch and Jody - revised script., 1974 Feb 12. (Box 5)
  - Quicksilver - Slay it Again, Sam script., 1984 Oct 8. (Box 7)
  - Reckoning - presentation., 1966-1967. (Box 7)
  - Shake and Baker-script and budget., March 1987. (Box 7)
  - SKAG production information., 1979 Aug 1. (Box 7)
  - Thriller-Fangoria article regarding Douglas Benton., 1996 Aug. (Box 4)
  - Thriller and Fangoria magazine and article., 1996-1997. (Box 4)
  - Transplant-script., 1978 Nov 10. (Box 7)
  - Transplant -production budget., no dates. (Box 7)
  - Wide Country-cast sheets., 1961-1963. (Box 4)
  - Wide Country-My Candle Burns at Both Ends script., 1962 Oct 30. (Box 4)
  - Wide Country-Patrol (The) script., 1962 Aug 2. (Box 4)
  - Wide Country-The Story of the Patrol story idea., no dates. (Box 4)
- Blackjack Productions.
  - Blackjack Productions Inc. corporate records., 1978. (Box 22)
    Article of incorporation Bylaws, certificate, and other documents.
  - Doug Benton, Blackjack Production, Warner Brothers memo., 1979 Nov 5. (Box 22)
  - Joyce Ottum - See the Kid Run correspondence., 1988. (Box 22)
  - Network series development., 1986 Mar 31. (Box 22)
  - Production Status Report., 1989 Feb 9. (Box 22)
  - Status Reports for Blackjack Productions., 1981. (Box 6)
  - Terminated Defined Benefit Pension Plan., 1988 Sept 2. (Box 22)
  - William Morris Agency contract (Clause 9)., 1977-1987. (Box 24)
  - William Morris Agency Contracts., 1980 and 1983. (Box 24)
  - William Morris Agency submissions., 1980. (Box 22)
- Projects in Development.
  - All Gods and Goddesses (O'Brien) - outline and 2 screenplays., no dates. (Box 6)
  - All the Gods and Goddesses - scripts., 1968 June 28. (Box 9)
  - All the Gods and Goddesses - scripts., no dates. (Box 9)
  - All the Gods and Goddesses - scripts., no dates. (Box 9)
  - Apache Flats - 3 treatments., 1980 March and June. (Box 6)
  - Apache Flats - treatment., 1978 and 1980. (Box 9)
  - Big Hitch - 3 reader's reports., 1980 July 11. (Box 6)
  - Black Jack and the Bandit - script., ca. 1985. (Box 8)
  - Black Jack and the Bandit - script., 1979 July 8. (Box 8)
  - Bravos (The) - presentation (2 copies)., no dates. (Box 9)
  - Buddy Holly Story - script., 1973 Jan 30. (Box 9)
  - Camera 50 - correspondence., 1989 Mar 1. (Box 24)
  - Catch Me; Kill Me - script., ca. 1981. (Box 9)
  - Comanche Keller - presentation for television series., no dates. (Box 10)
  - Comanche Keller (J. Gillis)- 5 presentations, outline and correspondence., 1981-1982. (Box 6)
  - Condemned to Life - story idea., no dates. (Box 10)
  - Correspondence., 1968-1999. (Box 24)
  - Coward! (Janet Meyers) treatment., 1980 Sept 22. (Box 6)
  - Day Late (A) - script and Carolyn Doty notes., 1980-1981. (Box 21)
  - Day Late (A) - scripts and what appears to be suggested changes., 1980-1981. (Box 21)
    4 scripts
  - Dead President - 2 scripts., no dates. (Box 8)
    See also: Rare Coin Score, Rare Coin Heist, and Caper.
  - Dead President - annotated script., no dates. (Box 8)
  - Dead Presidents - script., no dates. (Box 10)
  - Debut and Finale - project feedback., 1995 Jan 27. (Box 10)
  - Directors Guild 1981 DGA Basic Agreement. (Box 24)
  - Douglas Benton - Barry Perelman Contract., 1989 Mar 1. (Box 24)
  - Farmer's Hotel (The) - annotated script., no dates. (Box 6)
  - Farmer's Hotel (The) - script., no dates. (Box 10)
  - Farmer's Hotel (The) - script., no dates. (Box 6)
  - Fred C. Dobbs Project (Feigelson/ Benton)., no dates. (Box 6)
  - Have you Met Miss Jones? - presentation., 1981 Dec 1. (Box 10)
  - Have You Seen Miss Jones? (Dan Benton)- 4 outlines., 1981. (Box 6)
  - Helix Pictures Inc. - projects and resumes., no dates. (Box 24)
  - Helldorado - concept., 1971 July 30. (Box 10)
  - Hollywood Six - concept., 1981. (Box 10)
    See also: The Junkyard.
  - Holographic notes., no dates. (Box 24)
  - Homicide Team: Female Style (Bill Davidson)- treatment., 1981. (Box 6)
  - In This Our Life - script., 1941 Oct 3. (Box 12)
    See also: The Serpent's Tooth.
  - Ivy League (The) - presentation., 1980 June 25. (Box 10)
  - Ivy League (The) presentation for television series., 1980 June 25. (Box 6)
  - Jim Fitzpatrick article., 1981 Aug 14. (Box 6)
  - Junkyard (The) - script., ca. 1981. (Box 10)
    See also: Hollywood Six.
  - Limousine - story idea., no dates. (Box 10)
  - Looking for Ginger North reader's report., 1980 Mar 25. (Box 22)
  - Madeleine Barrie M.D. - 2 outlines and a presentation., 1980. (Box 23)
  - Me & His Highness - story idea., 1971 Nov 1. (Box 10)
  - Napa Valley - story idea., 1980 May 9. (Box 10)
  - Napa Valley memo., 1980 Mar 4. (Box 23)
  - NBC - Budget Master Summary Report., 1987 Apr 9. (Box 24)
  - Patsy Cline Story (The) - story idea., no dates. (Box 10)
  - Production Budgets., 1979, 1981, and 1982. (Box 23)
    Appear to be for SKAG, Victims, Helix, M.A.D.D, In our Hands, and
  - Properties available for production listing., no dates. (Box 22)
  - Psychic Who Helps Police clipping and photocopy., 1980 Mat 11. (Box 23)
  - Rare Coin Heist by Douglas Benton., ca. 1972. (Box 8)
    See also: Dead President, Rare Coin Score, and Caper.
  - Rare Coin Score (The) - 2 reader's reports., 1968 Oct 3. (Box 23)
    See also: Dead President, Rare Coin Heist, and Caper
  - Rare Coin Score (The) - reader's report and memo from Barbara Schultz., no dates. (Box 8)
  - Razor Cut - screenplay., 1981. (Box 11)
  - Razor Cut - screenplay (2 items - 1 annotated)., 1981 Nov 23. (Box 11)
  - Razor Cut - screenplay and script pages (2 folders)., 1981. (Box 11)
  - Research., 1969-1980. (Box 24)
  - Resumes., no dates. (Box 22)
    Talent and production resumes.
  - Rolling Stone - concept., 1964 June 3. (Box 22)
  - S.U.R.F. - 3 scripts and presentation., no dates. (Box 13)
  - Salem's Lot - Preliminary casting suggestions., 1980 Feb 4. (Box 12)
  - Salems Lot -2 series storylines., no dates. (Box 12)
    By Daniel Benton
  - Scarecrow (G. M. White) - conversation and 2 scripts., 1972 and 1982. (Box 23)
  - Scrolls of Socrates (The) - script., no dates. (Box 23)
  - Serpent's Tooth - screenplay (3 folders)., ca. 1941. (Box 12)
    See also: In This Our Life.
  - Slasher - script., 1981. (Box 12)
  - Smart Money - presentation., no dates. (Box 12)
  - Smart Money (R. Van Scoyk) treatment., no dates. (Box 23)
  - Strange Dimensions (J. D. Feigelson) - memo and proposal., ca. 1980. (Box 23)
  - Studs Brannigan - presentation and Barton/ Kurzfeld comments., ca. 1980. (Box 12)
  - Studs Brannigan (Benton/ Gillis) top sheet., 1980 Dec 29. (Box 23)
  - To Die at Happy End - script and 3 photographs., ca. 1972. (Box 13)
  - Unidentified script pages., no dates. (Box 22)
    Unspecified.
  - Unidentified story clues., no dates. (Box 24)
  - Universal City Studios reader's reports., 1966, 1970, and 1972. (Box 22)
  - Untitled script pages., no date. (Box 9)
    May be for project in development.
  - Verdict Is (The) - presentation., 1975 June 23. (Box 13)
  - Winter and Spring of Madeleine Barry M.D. (The) - 3 scripts., 1978 June 12. (Box 12)
  - Projects in Development.
- Submissions to Benton.
  - A-B., 1970s-1990s. (Box 13)
  - C-D., 1970s-1990s. (Box 14)
  - E-F., 1970s-1990s. (Box 15)
  - G-I., 1970s-1990s. (Box 16)
  - I, K-M., 1970s-1990s. (Box 17)
  - M, P, R, S., 1970s-1990s. (Box 18)
  - S., 1970s-1990s. (Box 19)
  - T, V, W and Untitled., 1970s-1990s. (Box 20)
  - Correspondence from Benton., 1980-1982. (Box 22)
    May be related to submissions
  - Doug Benton Correspondence., 1980-1982. (Box 6)
  - Dragon Lady by Daniel Benton., no dates. (Box 14)
  - Flight of the North Star - script., no dates. (Box 22)
  - Healing of Lia synopsis., 1981 Apr 23. (Box 22)
  - Mackerel Plaza (The) by Peter De Vries (photocopy of publication)., 1957-1958. (Box 21)
  - Rare Coin Score (The) - by Richard Stark (photocopy of publication)., no dates. (Box 7)
    See also: Dead President and Caper.
  - Scorpio script., no dates. (Box 22)
  - Stepping - reader's report and review., no dates. (Box 22)
  - Submission Correspondence from Benton., 1980-1982. (Box 6)
  - Traveling Man (The) by John Reese., 1968. (Box 21)
  - Twilight Zone - 2 scripts., no dates. (Box 21)
  - Virgil (The) by R.C. Reynolds - gallery proof., ca. 1985. (Box 21)